lyeh Onyewuchi Gabriel

Front End Engineer

Linkedln: linkedin.com/in/gabriel-iyeh/, Github: https://github.com/gabrieliyeh, Email: gabrieliyehlive@gmail.com, Phone: +2348082956821, +2349060708297.

Experience Summary

I am a professional and product-oriented Front End Engineer with 5+ years of experience acquired in various fast-paced, dynamic, and ever-changing settings. My diverse background includes working with Fintech startups and large scale enterprises. I have successfully worked with and led teams in building pixel perfect and functional user-friendly interfaces, optimising web application speed and performance. I focus on achieving results and a desire to bring professional value through creative solutions to problems. I always strive to be an indispensable team member of any company.

Core Competencies

Front-End: Javascript(ES6+), Typescript, React JS, React Native, Next JS, Vue JS, HTML5, Redux, Redux Toolkit, RTK, Vuex, React Query, SWR, Zustand, Context API.

UI-Libraries: CSS3/SCSS/SASS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, Element UI Ant Design, GSAP, Framer Motion.

Others: Node JS, Express, GraphQL, Docker, Agile Methodology, Web Performance Optimization (WPO), SCRUM and Agile Methodology, DOM Manipulation, E2E Testing, Esbuild, Vite, Webpack, Babel, CI/CD, FIGMA, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), Accessibility(a1ly) and Internalization(i18n), Cross-browser compatibility, PWAs, RESTFUL API, GIT, Azure DevOps Cloud, Vitest, Jest, Jasmine.

Other Skills

Effective Communication, Emotional Intelligence, Growth Mindset, Collaboration, Mentoring, Critical Thinking, Strong Interpersonal Skills, OwnerShip Mindset.

Professional Experience

Zenith Bank Plc | Front-End Lead| December 2021 - Present.

- Develop and manage user-facing web applications that serve over 2.4 million customers across
 E-business, retail banking, and credit card services, providing value to the business and its customers.
- Defined and enforced engineering best practices in projects to ensure that projects are delivered
 on time and with the best possible solutions, providing technical mentorship to fellow team
 members whenever possible to help the team and company grow rapidly.
- Worked on the design, Front End architecture and development of various payment systems and solutions Including the revamp of the global payment gateways.

- Maintain the bank's MFB's Card Portal. Developed and deployed batch request features for the MFB's Card Portal. That currently processes over 900,000 requests on a weekly basis, making debit and credit card requests accessible to millions of merchants and customers.
- Eliminated redundant application codes on old code bases that saved us about 20% of the size and the load time of every page bundle and build.

HTML5, CSS3, React JS, React Native, Next JS, Vue JS, Azure, Javascript(ES6+), Typescript, Ant Design, React Query, Zustand, Vitest, Jasmine, PWA, REST API, Redux, Tailwind, SWR.

Bulb - UK, Remote | Front-End Engineer | August 2020 - October 2021.

- Responsible for end-to-end UI/UX development and implementation, including layout and product communication. Was focused primarily on front-end development for web applications, ensuring seamless user experiences and efficient interface functionality.
- Contributed to the development team that delivered a Customer Account Portal that provides customers with a convenient and secure platform to manage their energy accounts.
- Successfully shipped and deployed a Smart Meter Integration feature, reaching and benefiting over 300,000 users across the EU and UK, resulting in increased energy efficiency and enhanced customer satisfaction.

HTML5, CSS3, React JS, Next JS, Git, Tailwind, Javascript(ES6+), Docker, Typescript, React Native Jest, Material UI.

OPAY - Contract | Software Developer | July 2019 - August 2020.

- Worked on the development and maintenance of large-scale fin-tech software solutions ranging from Payment and Transaction Management, actively participating in the entire software lifecycle.
- Implemented robust and performant new features in a Service Oriented Architecture (SOA),
 profiling, planning, and testing features, and revamped existing ones.
- Was part of a team of skilled engineers that built an aggregator management application that boosted the efficiency of managing POS terminal activities for merchants. The app reduced the time required for terminal management by 40%, resulting in about a 30% increase in transaction volumes for the company.
- Liaised closely with product managers, designers and backend engineers to transform business requirements into software products for millions of customers.

HTML5, CSS3, Vue JS, Javascript, Typescript, React Js, Material UI, Git, Jest, Jasmine, Tailwind, Element UI.

Education

Bachelor of Science Computer Systems and Software | African University of Technology and Management (GASA FORMATION). | December 2017.